这便是蟹堡王，堪称卡通史上最具代表性的餐厅
This is the Krusty Krab, the most iconic restaurant in cartoon history.
既然它如此大名鼎鼎，想必大伙儿都对它了如指掌了吧
So with how iconic it is, you'd think we'd know it front to back, right?
大错特错
Wrong!
话说，你对这个房间还有印象吗
Tell me, do you remember this room?
好吧，或许你还记得那个房间，但这个呢
Okay, maybe you remember that room. But what about this room?
也罢，那大概只是另一间储藏室
Well, alright, that's probably just another storage closet.
任何餐厅里这种犄角旮旯总会有那么几个
Any restaurant has a couple of those lying around the place.
但难道每家餐厅都有这样的密室吗
But does every restaurant have a secret room like this?
如果你觉得蟹堡王的地板下面
In case you were thinking it could make sense that the Krusty Krab
是一个百尺之深的巨型油污陷阱也合情合理
was a giant hundred-foot-deep grease trap under its floorboards,
那我得告诉你个坏消息
I've got some bad news for you.
没错，那儿可看不见什么油污地牢
Yep, no grease dungeon visible there.
不然它早就把蟹堡王底下的洞穴撑爆了
It'd be bursting right into the caverns underneath the Krusty Krab.
如果你还不知道的话，那地方也确实存在
Which, if you didn't know, also exists.
而这仅仅是我们发现问题的开始
And that's just the start of the issues we've got.
相信我，蟹老板床垫下藏着多少私房钱
Trust me, for every dollar Krabs his stash under his mattress,
这家餐厅的存在就有多少矛盾之处
there's an inconsistency with this restaurant's existence.
所以都围过来吧，蟹堡王的伙计们
So gather around, Krusty crew.
今天我就要告诉你们蟹堡王这家店
I'm gonna tell you every reason why the Krusty Krab
究竟为何丁点儿逻辑都讲不通
just don't make any frackin' sense whatsoever.
不过在此之前，我们先来理清一些基本设定
But before we go any further, let's get the basics out of the way.
这张图，大概就是我们能找到的关于蟹老板摇钱树最官方的布局图了
This is about as close as we're gonna get to a canon layout of Eugene Krab's moneymaker.
一层楼，四个房间
One floor, four rooms.
这儿是个用餐区
We've got the dining area.
卫生间
The restroom.
蟹老板的办公室
Mr. Krab's office.
当然，还有厨房
And, of course, the kitchen.
如果想抠亿点细节，我们还可以看看后面的垃圾箱区域
And if we wanna get ultra-detailed, we can also take a look at the back where the dumpsters are,
就像《脏话》那一集里演的
like in the episode Sailor Mouth.
好了，单看这份布局图，你可能会和我想的一样
Now, okay, going off on that list alone, you're probably thinking the same thing as me.
这里面少了很多房间
There's a lot of missing rooms.
没错，确实如此
And yes, there are.
不过在此之前，我们其实刚刚在垃圾箱区域的片段里就发现了一个大问题
Before we get to that, we actually just saw a pretty big issue in that clip of the dumpster area.
看看你能不能发现
Let's see if you can figure it out.
这是另一段来自《咬一口》那集的餐厅后场景
Here's another clip of the back of the restaurant from the episode Just One Bite.
注意到什么了吗
Notice anything?
嗯，不仅仅是垃圾箱不见了
No, it's not just the fact that the dumpster isn't there.
实际上，它在这部剧里总是四处移动
It moves all the time in this show, actually.
看吧
See?
这里真正重要的区别在于，整个后门都消失了
No, the real important difference there is the fact that the entire back door is missing.
在《脏话》的那个场景里
In the scene from Sailor Mouth?
就这么凭空消失了
Just gone.
而且这扇门的存在可不是一次性的
And it's not like the door's presence was a one-time thing.
在《蟹堡乐园》这一集里它又出现了
Here it is again in the episode Krabbyland.
当然，后门现在从木头的变成了金属的
Sure, the back door is now metal instead of wood,
而且窗户也和我们在《咬一口》里看到的完全相反
and the window is on the complete opposite side as we saw in Just One Bite.
但你知道吗
But you know what?
这个问题总比连门都没有要好得多
That's a better problem to have than just not having a door at all.
如果你想看看后门和垃圾箱同时存在的世界
And in case you wanted to see a world where there's a back door and a dumpster at the same time,
《冰库历险记》这一集满足你
the episode Truth or Square got you covered.
一目了然
Plain as day.
有证据表明它们可以同时存在
There's evidence that they can all exist at the same time.
如果你想跟我辩论，请在下方评论区留下你的姓名，地址和信用卡信息
If you want to debate me, please leave your name, address, and credit card info in the comments below,
我会在5到18000个工作日内回复你
and I'll get back to you within 5-18,000 business days.
千万别这么做，求你了，别留
Don't actually do that, please. Don't leave that.
好了，不说后面了
But alright, moving away from the back,
我们来看看蓝图上没有提到的那些房间
let's start looking at some of the actual rooms that aren't mentioned in that blueprint,
就从最“酷”的那个开始，冷库
starting with the coolest of the bunch, the freezer.
看吧，最“酷”的
See? Coolest?
你们怎么不笑呢
Why aren't you laughing?
冷库没出现在图上还挺奇怪的
So, it's kinda odd that the freezer is missing there.
对吧，我的意思是，它可是在一些经典剧集中出现过的
Right? I mean, this has been in some iconic episodes.
比如它在《SB-129》里的首次亮相
Take, for instance, its first appearance back in SB-129.
章鱼哥为了躲避海绵宝宝和派大星，逃进了蟹堡王的厨房
Squiddy's doing his best to get away from Spongebob and Patrick before escaping into the kitchen of the Krusty Krab,
然后……
and...
就是它，我们熟悉又喜爱的冷库
There it is! The freezer as we know and love it.
可惜章鱼哥还没来得及逃出去，门把手就断了
Unfortunately for Squidward, the handle breaks off before he can escape,
他被冰封了2000年，然后……
he's frozen for 2,000 years, and...
剩下的故事你们都知道了
Well, you know the rest.
谢谢你啊，章鱼哥
Thank you, Squiddy.
但问题来了
But here's the thing.
仅凭那一集，我们根本看不出这冷库到底在哪
From that episode alone, we really didn't get a good idea of where this freezer is.
我们只知道它在厨房里，但除此之外就知之甚少了
We know it's in the kitchen, but not all too much else.
不过事实证明，我们在《肮脏的汉堡》这一集里找到了答案
Well, as it turns out, we get the answer as to where exactly this place is in the episode Nasty Patty.
海绵宝宝和蟹老板把卫生检察员的“尸体”塞进了冷库
After Spongebob and Mr. Krab have stuffed the health inspector's body in the freezer,
至少他们是这么认为的
or so they think.
尽管经历了一场僵尸惊魂，我们总算知道蟹堡王冷库的位置了
Despite a zombie scare, we finally know where the Krusty Krab's freezer is.
根据我们能看到收银台的视角
Based on how we're able to see the lookout of the register,
可以推断出冷库就在厨房区域的正后方
we can see that the freezer is directly towards the back of the kitchen area.
如果你想进一步求证，在《冰库历险记》里证据确凿
And if you want further proof of this, here it is plain and simple in Truth or Square.
是的，如果你没从那和《SB-129》里如出一辙断掉的门把手看出来的话
And yes, if you couldn't tell from the handle breaking off just as it did in SB 129,
这的确就是那个冷库
this is the freezer.
够清楚了吧
Pretty cut and dry, right?
毫无疑问，蟹堡王有一个冷库
There is no doubt the Krusty Krab has a freezer.
它的位置已经确认，而且在大多数剧集里看起来都大同小异
It's got a confirmed location that looks pretty similar in most episodes' appearances.
还能有什么能撼动这个房间的存在呢
What could possibly throw any wrench in this room's existence?
好吧，我有个问题请教一下
Well, I've got a request for you.
请解释一下《回归自然》这一集里的这个镜头
Explain this shot from the episode Nature Pants.
暂停，看看蟹堡王厨房的后墙
Pause. Take a look at the back wall of the Krusty Krab.
先别管后门又不见了这事，扪心自问
Disregard that the back door is yet again missing and ask yourself,
如果那扇窗户直接通向外面，那冷库去哪了
if that window leads directly to the outside, where is the freezer room?
它必然是一个从蟹堡王后面伸出来的大长方形房间
It'd have to be a big ol' rectangular room jutting out of the back of the Krusty Krab.
而我们已经一次又一次地看到，这家餐厅根本没有这种结构
And as we've seen time and time again, this is just something that the restaurant just doesn't have.
而且这可不是什么无足轻重的小房间
And this isn't some small minor room either.
它出场次数不少，而且通常被描绘成一个相当大的地方
It shows up a fair amount of times and is usually seen as a pretty sizable location.
绝不算小
Not small, by any means.
所以，这个房间要么在某个口袋次元里，要么就根本不存在
So, this room's either in a pocket dimension, or it doesn't exist.
你选一个吧
Take your pick.
我还是选口袋次元好了
I'll go with pocket dimension, though.
我可真是恨透了非欧几何
I frickin' hate non-Euclidean geometry.
说到非欧几何的房间
Now, if we're talking about rooms that are non-Euclidean,
我们就必须提到整个系列中最经典的一次性房间之一
we gotta bring up one of the most iconic one-off rooms in the entire series,
蟹黄堡仓库
the Paddy Vault.
它的问题……其实很简单
It's used... is kinda simple.
我们都知道蟹堡王厨房的高度
We all know the height of the Krusty Krab's kitchen.
是的，不是很高
Yeah, not super tall.
你看，这可是厨房的官方背景图
I mean, here's the literal background art for the kitchen.
一点也不高
Not tall at all.
然后……
And then...
我们看到了蟹黄堡仓库……
We got the Paddy Vault...
这看起来足足有……
That looks just about too...
它比厨房能容纳的任何东西都要高出三倍
It's three times taller than anything the kitchen should be able to hold,
但当你往里看时，情况就更糟了
but it only gets worse when you take a look inside.
这种房间简直可以配个跳水板了
That's the type of room that could use a diving board.
你可以学史高治·麦克老鸭，在那些汉堡里游泳
You could pull a Scrooge McDuck and start swimming in all those paddies.
当然，前提是你愿意浑身沾满陈年汉堡的油腻
If you wanted to cover yourself in weak old burger grease, that is.
所以问题就在于，又一次
So yeah, the issue here is that once again,
如果这个地方真的存在于蟹堡王
if this place really existed in the Krusty Krab,
那它早就突破天花板了
it'd be bursting from the ceiling.
而我们知道这是不可能发生的
And we know that's something that can't be happening
因为蟹堡王整个系列中最不合逻辑的部分
because of the most illogical portion of the Krusty Krab in the entire series,
我们稍后会讲到
but we'll get to that in due time.
但我们的布局图上还漏掉了另一个重要的房间
But there's another important missing room from that diagram of ours.
储藏室
The storage room.
或者说……储藏室们
Or... storage rooms.
我不知道，这事儿很复杂
I don't know, it's complicated.
还记得视频开头的这些片段吗
So remember these clips from the intro of this video?
那个片段出自《蟹老板的冒牌货》这一集
That one's from the episode, Imitation Crabs.
注意看，门是通向餐厅用餐区的
Notice how the door leads to the dining area of the restaurant,
因为我们能看到外面的大窗户
as we can see the big window to the outside?
现在再看看《我要检举你》这一集里的这个片段
Now take a look at this clip from Accidents Will Happen.
是的，严格来说
Yeah, in all technicality,
这是两个不同的房间
these are two different rooms.
那一个明显在厨房的后面——
That one is clearly at the back of the kitchen,
天知道——可能就在冷库应该在的位置
probably where the freezer belongs for all we know.
我的意思是，它看起来和冷库差不多大
I mean, it looks to be as big as the freezer.
看看这个房间有多宽敞
Look at how hefty this room is!
再说一次，这玩意儿应该从建筑后面伸出来
Again, this should be jutting out of the back of the building,
然而并没有
but nope.
我们知道蟹堡王的形状
We know the shape of the Krusty Krab.
过去是，现在是，将来也永远是一个大号捕蟹笼
The crap it is, was, and forever will be just a giant crab trap.
什么，你不知道它是个捕蟹笼吗
What, you didn't know it was a crab trap?
好吧，现在你知道了
Well, the more you know.
如果两个储藏室还不够你瞧的
And if two storage rooms isn't enough for you,
那为什么不再加第三个呢
why not toss in the third?
这是《化敌为友》一集里的另一个
Here's another one of the episode, New Leaf.
在我说到显而易见的问题之前
So before I get to the obvious,
我们得先谈谈那个机器人蟹老板
we gotta address the fact that the robot crabs
就是《蟹老板的冒牌货》那一集里的，居然就坐在这间储藏室里
from the Imitation Crabs episode is sitting in that storage room.
编剧们一定是在嘲讽我们
The showrunners have gotta be taunting us!
把一个来自某集的机器人——那一集里的储藏室本就前后不一
Including the robot from an episode that features their inconsistent storage room
——放到了另一集里，一个同样前后不一的储藏室里
in another episode with an inconsistent storage room.
他们在玩弄我
They're toying with me!
总之，言归正传
Anywho, time for the obvious.
如果我们回头看那张蓝图
If we look back at that blueprint layout,
这个储藏室的位置应该是卫生间
this closet is where the bathroom should be.
所以，我们又得到了一个完全颠覆任何形式空间逻辑的房间
So, yet again, we've got a room that just obliterates any form of spatial logic.
真棒
Lovely.
蟹老板从不遵守规则
Eugene Krabs doesn't care for rules,
无论是垄断法还是万有引力
whether they apply to monopolies or gravity.
哦，为了好玩
Oh, and just for fun,
这里还有另一个完全没有明确位置的壁橱
here's another closet that has no precise location whatsoever.
请欣赏《章鱼威廉回来了》的片段
Take it away, clip from Squilliam Returns.
关于那个我真没什么好说的
I don't really have much to say about that one.
很好笑，我承认，但它依然无厘头
It's funny, I'll give it that, but it still makes zero sense.
这些卡通里的壁橱到底是怎么回事
What is it with cartoon closets, man?
好了，在我们讨论蟹堡王中那个完全摧毁逻辑感的方面之前
Now, before we get to the aspect of the Krusty Krab that just completely destroys any sense of logic,
我们先来快速过一遍一些被遗忘却同样匪夷所思的蟹堡王房间
let's do a quick lightning round for some of the forgotten yet still incomprehensible rooms of the Krusty Krab.
这是垃圾房，仅在《白吃客》一集中出现
Here's the trash room, only appearing in the episode Pat No Pay.
说实话，那个房间看起来甚至没有入口
Not gonna lie, that room didn't look like it even had an entrance.
但你瞧，它确实有，而且还很难错过
But lo and behold, it does, and it's hard to miss.
我的意思是，这么大的红字，如果这扇门在别处出现过，你不可能看不到
I mean, with big red letters, there's no doubt you'd be able to see this door if it had any other appearances.
但就像这个地方的许多其他房间一样，它就这么消失了
But like so many other rooms in this place, it just disappears.
海绵宝宝在那个片段里到底是从哪儿出来的
Where was Spongebob even coming from in that clip?
那看起来像一条空空如也的走廊
It looked like a completely blank hallway.
现在，要说蟹堡王里的一次性房间
Now, we couldn't be talking about one-off rooms in the Krusty Krab
就不能忘了车库，那里可是我们最爱的机动三明治的家
and forget the garage, home of everyone's favorite motorized sandwich.
但是，要怎么去车库开那辆美味快餐车呢
But, how do you get to the garage to access the Paddy Wagon?
你得往下走
Well, you gotta go down.
一直往下
Way down.
是的，他们基本上是下了两层楼梯才到那个车库
Yeah, they essentially went down two flights of stairs to get to that garage.
所以蟹堡王显然还有个地下室
So the Krusty Krab has a basement, apparently.
好吧，行
Right, okay.
那么，他们到底是怎么把车开出餐厅的
Well then, I mean, how exactly did they get the car out of the restaurant?
他们把车开上电梯和消防滑竿，然后从一楼的窗户撞了出去
They take the car up the elevator and the fire poles to bust it through the window of the first floor.
我可没懵，懵的是你
I'm not confused, you are.
你知道吗，一个三明治能开动本身就相当无厘头
You know what? It doesn't make any sense that you can drive a sandwich in the first place.
我干嘛还要质疑区区一个车库呢
Why should I question the garage, of all things?
现在我们来看看蟹老板的秘密巢穴
Now we've got Mr. Krabs' secret lair.
你问他在这里干什么
What is he doing here, you ask?
好吧，让蟹老板自己解释
Well, I'll let Eugene explain.
哇
Whoa!
哦，蟹老板，这看起来太疯狂了
Oh, Mr. Krabs, this looks like madness.
这是我的秘密实验室，我在这里做食物实验
It's me secret lab, where I experiment on food.
是的，那个房间就像听起来那样，充满科学怪人的气息
Yes, that room is as Frankenstein-y as it sounds.
在珊迪的帮助下
And with the help of Sandy,
这里烹制的实验汉堡把大部分比奇堡居民变成了可怕的汉堡变种人
the experimental Paddy's cook down here turned most of Bikini Bottom into hideous Paddy mutants.
真是笔好投资啊，蟹老板，你肯定很高兴建了这个房间吧
Real solid investment, Krabs. Bet you're glad you had this room constructed.
好了，抛开变种人末日不谈，我们有更重要的事情
Okay, but moving beyond the mutant apocalypse, we've got bigger priorities.
这个实验室到底在哪里
Where exactly is this lab located?
就在海绵宝宝烤炉的右边，冷库的下面
Directly to the right of Spongebob's Grill, underneath the freezer.
让我提醒你一下，通常在海绵宝宝烤炉右边的是什么
Let me remind you what's usually to the right of Spongebob's Grill.
蟹老板的办公室
Mr. Krabs' office.
尽管他是个冷酷的老板，但这不代表他的休息室就是个冷库
As cold of a boss as he is, that doesn't mean his lounge is a freezer.
接下来是《咬一口》里一个稍纵即逝的房间
Here's a blink-and-you'll-miss-it room from Just One Bite.
焚化炉室
The incinerator room.
再说一次，我对此无话可说
Again, I got really nothing to say here.
海绵宝宝只是跳到了画面的一边
Smunchbob just jumps to the side of the frame,
突然间他就到了一个不该出现在餐厅的房间里
and all of a sudden he's in a room that probably shouldn't be in a restaurant.
怎么，你想让我猜猜这个会在哪儿吗
What, did you want me to guess where this would be?
你觉得这个鬼地方能在哪儿
Where the heck do you think this room would be?
我的猜测和你的一样没谱，伙计
My guess is as good as yours, bucko.
在我们探讨最不合逻辑的房间之前
And before we tackle the most illogical room of all,
我们先来谈谈一个实际上可能还算说得通的
let's talk about one that actually could kinda make sense.
员工休息室
The employee break room.
它只在《好好休息喔》这一集中出现过，但绝对留下了深刻印象
It was only shown in the episode Breakin, but it definitely made its mark.
蟹老板会把它藏在一百万层墙纸下面，倒也合理
It only makes sense that crabs would hide that under a million layers of wallpaper.
它那么小也就不奇怪了
It also makes sense how small the thing is.
被挤在卫生间和厨房之间，你的尺寸自然就受限了，不是吗
Being smooshed between the bathroom and kitchen kinda limits your size, doesn't it?
但是嘿，你知道吗
But hey, you know what?
和我们谈论过的巨大蟹黄堡仓库和冷库相比，它已经很合理了
It makes sense compared to the giant paddy vaults and freezers we've talked about.
我觉得我们不必担心这个地方会随机伸出来一块
I don't think we gotta worry about random jutting out with this place.
是时候谈谈那个东西了
It's time we talked about it.
蟹堡王里最愚蠢，最荒谬绝伦的部分
The absolute dumbest, most nonsensical piece of the Krusty Krab.
它的通风管道
It's air vents.
它可是大家最爱的剧集《冰库历险记》里的主角
The star of the show in everybody's favorite episode, Truth or Square.
其实翻到这里我才想起来这就是央视放的《海绵宝宝狂欢周年庆》
但是我都按维基百科剧集列表翻译下来了，就这样吧
那么，这些通风管道到底有多么前后矛盾呢
So just how inconsistent are these vents exactly?
它们甚至不在逻辑上应在的位置……
While they aren't even where they should be, logistically...
地下的通风管道
Underground air ducts?
我猜，也算合理吧
I guess that makes sense?
但我觉得把通风系统建在地上会简单得多，也便宜得多，对吧
But I feel like it'd just be a whole lot easier and cheaper to have above-ground ventilation, right?
我的意思是，我们都知道蟹老板最爱削减成本了
I mean, we know crabs is all about cost-cutting.
果不其然，在这集的后面，蟹堡王一行人被困在冷库里之后
Well, sure enough, later in the episode, after the Krusty crew gets stuck in the freezer,
你可能会觉得他们现在该换掉那个有问题的把手了吧
you'd think they'd have replaced the faulty handles by now,
我们得到了一个真正令人震惊的发现
we get a real shocking revelation.
地上的通风口
Above-ground vents.
而且还是个迷宫般的存在
And a whole maze of them to boot!
没错，蟹老板的通风口实际上在天花板上
Yeah, Mr. Krab's vents are in fact in the ceiling,
尽管之前那张地图显示它们是埋在地下的
even though that map from earlier showed them as being buried.
奇了怪了，在这个场景的后面，蟹老板仍然坚称管道在地板下面
Heck, later on in this scene, the Krab still insists the shafts are under the floorboards,
尽管这完全说不通
even though it just makes zero sense.
再说一次，我想无需解释这样庞大的通风系统如何能塞进这么小的餐厅里
And again, I don't think I have to explain how a vent system this expansive could fit in a restaurant this small.
但是别担心，我不会抱怨那个，我会抱怨这个
But no, you don't gotta worry. Instead of whining about that, I'll whine about this instead.
所以……让我理一理
So... let me get this straight.
蟹老板有一个大到不可思议的通风系统，入口在一个位置不可思议的冷库里
Mr. Krabs has an impossibly huge ventilation system accessed through an impossibly placed freezer
而这个系统里还有一个不可能存在的保安室
that houses an impossible security room.
我本想质疑蟹老板为什么监视我们
I'd question why Mr. Krabs spies on us,
但坦白说，我对空间推理已经有太多疑问了，所以没必要再问了
but frankly, I'm asking enough questions about the spatial reasoning anyways, so there's no point.
如果你觉得这个房间可能在地下
In case you thought that this room possibly could be underground,
你知道的，也许那个迷宫般的通风井里有条路能把他们带下去
you know, maybe one of those pathways in that maze of a vent shaft took the Krusty crew down.
再想想吧，伙计
Think again, pal.
是的，他们出来了
Yep, there they go.
径直从一个靠近天花板的通风口钻了出来
Right through a vent towards the ceiling.
你知道，很多人不喜欢这一集，因为觉得它太长了，也不知道为啥
You know, a lot of people dislike this episode because it's too long, for some reason.
但我想你应该能猜到我个人为什么不喜欢它
But I think you can guess why I personally dislike it.
它把现实法则扔进了垃圾桶
It throws the laws of reality in the trash.
作为一个现实主义者，我对此深恶痛绝
As a realist, I resent things like that.
当然，前提是不好笑
If it's not funny, that is.
你看，像这样的东西我可以忍受一整天，因为它能让我笑
See, I can put up with stuff like this all day because it makes me laugh.
看吧，这就是为了搞笑而打破物理学
See, that's breaking physics for fun.
可怜的章鱼哥又成了牺牲品
At Squidward's expense, poor guy.
但今天我要说的就这么多了
But that's all I got for you today.
如果你想看更多这样荒诞不经的航海故事
And if you want to see more nautical nonsense like this,
就去看看屏幕上的视频吧
check out the video on screen now.
那么下次再见
Until next time,
回见您内
VASIL AND LABERS!
感谢观看
Thanks, thank you for watching.